MICHAEL HEYLMUN

DATA ANALYST

CONTACT 231-670-4511 michael.heylmun@gmail.com www.michaelheylmun.com Grand Rapids, MI 49506

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, R, C, SAS, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Python Libraries: Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn

Data Science Skills: Data cleaning, statistical analysis, and data visualization
Version control with Git and Github

Software & Tools: Power BI, Databricks, AutoCAD, SolidWorks, Microsoft Office, Slack, Linux, Windows 11

EDUCATION

Grand Valley State University

Bachelor of Science in Statistics

Minors: Engineering Science and Mathematics Graduated April 2024

Relevant Coursework:

- · Intermediate Applied Statistics
- Mathematical Statistics I
- Mathematical Statistics II
- Design of Experiments
- Applied Regression Analysis
- Statistical Computing and Graphics with R

- Calculus 3
- Linear Algebra and Differential Equations
- Operations Research

REFERENCES

Available upon request.

PROFILE

Motivated and technically skilled Statistics graduate proficient in Python, R, C, SAS, SQL, and Power BI, with a strong background in statistical analysis, data visualization, and data manipulation. Experienced in utilizing Python libraries such as Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, and Scikit-learn to analyze and interpret complex datasets. Actively applying object-oriented programming principles and pursuing machine learning and predictive modeling techniques to expand my data science toolkit.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Axis Automation | Walker, MI

CNC Machinist

August 2023 - Present

• Operate CNC machines to produce precision components for robotics systems.

Synthetik Applied Technologies | Remote (Austin, TX)

Internship

May 2022 - August 2022

- . Conducted simulations of detonations using BlastFOAM, validated data with GNUplot.
- Designed models with BlockMesh and Gmsh, contributing to data validation.
- Conducted research to assess the accuracy of existing models among other projects.

Viking Tool and Engineering | Whitehall, MI

Machinist

June 2019 - January 2021

• Operated milling machines, lathes, and grinders to fabricate components for molds

PROJECTS

Data Fest Competition

2024

- Participated in a national data analysis competition using data provided by CourseKata.
- Recommended that chapters 5 through 10 of their college textbook be made more
 challenging and thorough based on consistent activity scores and a significant drop in
 student engagement, measured by time spent per page, using R, SAS, and Tableau.
- Placed 2nd in visualizations and 1st in collegiality for teamwork among GVSU students.

Studying the Effects of FIT Classes on Academic Performance

Client: GVSU Movement Science Department

2024

- Analyzed the impact of taking a 1-credit FIT class during freshman year on academic success (GPA, retention rates, time to graduation) using R.
- Concluded that there's significant evidence that students that take a FIT class are
 more likely to be retained for a second year at GVSU.
- Presented findings at Student Scholars Day.

2023

America's Housing Market

- Analyzed U.S. Census data to study trends in housing and rent prices, identifying which demographics were most impacted by changes using R.
- Recognized as the top project in both class sections by the professor.